Misaka Mikoto, who thought her life had returned to normal, is once again disturbed by darkness.
（上条(かみじょう)）
平穏を取り戻したはずの
御坂美琴(みさか みこと)の日常に―
再び暗雲が立ちこめる
A mysterious organization is acting around the remains of Tree Diagram.
樹形図の設計者(ツリーダイアグラム)の残骸を巡って
暗躍する謎の組織
The Level 4 who uses Move Point, Musujime Awaki.
“座標移動(ムーブポイント)”を操るレベル４
結標淡希(むすじめ あわき)
そして 人知れず続く 御坂の孤独な
戦いをかいま見た白井黒子(しらい くろこ)は…
And Shirai Kuroko, who catches a glimpse into Misaka's lonely battle through her own covert actions...
～♪
#07 Move Point
Coordinate Movement
なによ
一般人なんていないじゃない
What?
None of them are civilians...
Seems like she underestimated my powers, assuming I wouldn't teleport myself away.
（結標）
私が自分自身を
テレポートさせることはないと―
タカをくくっていたみたいね
I can do it whenever I want.
その気になれば
いつだってできるのよ
If I just feel like it, regardless of the trauma...
その気になりさえすれば
トラウマなんて…
Is it not called trauma due to the fact that you cannot overcome it so easily?
（黒子）
そうそう克服できないから
“トラウマ”というのではなくて？
Two years ago, you sustained serious injuries after teleporting yourself.
２年前 あなたは 自分を
テレポートさせて重傷を負った
Did you perhaps make some sort of mistake during your coordinate calculations and run into a wall?
おおかた 座標の計算を誤って―
壁にでも
突っ込んでしまったんですの？
My, oh my, isn't that pathetic?
（黒子）いやはや お粗末ですこと
（結標）クッ…
（黒子）
慌てる必要はありませんわよ
急所は外してありますの
There is no reason to fret.
I avoided your vital areas.
Truthfully, all I am doing is repeating what you have done to me.
まあ やられた所に
そのまま お返ししただけですけど
Have this hemostatic.
これは止血剤
結構 効くんですのよ
It helps to prevent bleeding.
Now, if you would be so kind as to lay down and treat your wounds.
（黒子）
さあ　せいぜい床に這(は)いつくばって
傷の手当てでもしてくださいな
Once completed, we can consider ourselves even.
そこまでして
やっと おあいこですのよ
You must be quite fond of Tokiwadai's Ace.
（結標）
よほど あの常盤台(ときわだい)のエースに―
心酔しているのね
でも
そこまでして守る価値があるの？
However, is she really worth going this far to protect?
Is the Railgun's selfish yet sentimental dream world worth it?
超電磁砲(レールガン)が思い描く 身勝手で
おセンチで 絵空事しかない世界を
（黒子）
守りたいに決まってますの
But of course.
Albeit a selfish wish, it is one that Onee-sama desires.
どれだけ身勝手だとしても
お姉様は望んでいますの
A world where neither one of us interferes.
私や あなたが
こんなことをしないで済む状況を
By mere flick of a coin, she could destroy everything in her path if she so desired.
（黒子）
その気になれば コインひとつで
全てを粉々に打ち砕くことができる
Even so, Onee-sama is someone who can honestly say that she doesn't want to fight even in deepest despair.
それでも 争ってほしくないと―
どんな絶望の中でも 真顔で
言える人なんですのよ お姉様は
Do you truly think that I could just ignore those emotions?
その思いを
私が蹴るとでもお思いですの？
Now, I am going to have you return her life back to normal.
（黒子）
これから あなたを
日常へ帰してさし上げますわ
The life that someone, somewhere, dreamed of.
どこかで誰かが思い
この私が共感したとおりに
One that I support.
Then if I trample over those feelings...
ならば その思いを踏みにじれば…
（ライトの点滅音）
私の勝ちかしらね？
I wonder if I'll come out the winner?
ンッ！
（黒子）同じ手は二度と…
The same trick will not work a second time!
（黒子）
テレポートができない
I cannot teleport?!
What's wrong?
（結標）
どうしたの？　痛みでテレポートが
使えなくなっちゃったわけ？
Were you in so much pain that you lost your ability to teleport?
Hey, have you ever heard of this story?
（結標）
ねえ こんな話 知ってる？
"Once upon a time, there was a powerful Esper and an organization."
昔々 ある所に
強力な能力者と組織がありました
"The organization believed that, if they could increase the number of powerful Espers, they may gain immense powers."
組織は その能力者の数を増やせば
莫大(ばくだい)な力が得られると考え
"Many clones were produced."
たくさんのクローンを
こしらえました
（結標）
ところが 結果は さんざんでした
"But the results were horrible."
"The little lambs that were created didn't even have a percentage of the original's power."
出来上がった哀れな子羊たちは―
オリジナルの
１パーセントも満たない―
"They were complete failures."
とんだ出来損ないだったのです
"I will now organize what we know so far," says MISAKA-10032 while opening the network, calling out to its many members.
（御坂10032）
それでは
ここまでの情報を整理します
…と 御坂10032号は
ネットワークを介し―
不特定多数の個体に問いかけます
"Currently, only Academy City has the Remnant necessary to restore Tree Diagram."
現状 樹形図の設計者(ツリーダイアグラム)の
復元が可能な残骸(レムナント)は―
学園都市にある物だけ
"The name of the outside organization targeting it is 'Science Society.'"
それを狙う外部組織の名は科学結社
それで間違いありませんね？
"There's no mistake in that intel, is there?" confirms MISAKA-10032 again.
…と
御坂10032号は 再度 確認します
"There is certainly no mistake," affirms MISAKA-10044.
（御坂10044）
間違いありません
…と 御坂10044号は肯定します
"But 10032, you sustained a lot more damage than any of the others."
（御坂10744）
しかし 10032号
そちらは 全個体の中でも
特に肉体のダメージが大きく
"Shouldn't you remain in the hospital?" asks MISAKA-10744 worriedly.
治療に専念すべきでは？
…と 御坂10744号は
懸念を表明します
"It doesn't matter," replies MISAKA-10032, immediately.
かまいません
…と 御坂10032号は即答します
樹形図の設計者(ツリーダイアグラム)の復元だけは
絶対に阻止しなければならない
"The restoration of Tree Diagram must be prevented at all costs,"
says MISAKA-10032 as she reaffirms her determination, remembering the faces of that boy and girl.
…と 御坂10032号は―
あの少年と少女の顔を
思い出しながら―
決意を新たにします
"Understood. It's up to you then," nods MISAKA-14458 in agreement.
（御坂14458）
了解　あなたに一任します
…と 御坂14458号は
首を縦に振ります
"We'll leave it to you," agrees MISAKA-19002.
（御坂19002）
よろしくお願いします
…と 御坂19002号も賛同します
"MISAKA is also counting on you!" says MISAKA says MISAKA while making her request.
（ﾗｽﾄｵｰﾀﾞｰ）
ミサカもお願いするって
ミサカはミサカは頼んでみたり
（ﾗｽﾄｵｰﾀﾞｰ）
…ていうか ミサカも何かしたい
"No wait, MISAKA wants to do something too!"
"I can't just stay here and do nothing!" says MISAKA says MISAKA—
１人で じっとしているなんて
ミサカはミサカは…
Hey!
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）おい
（ﾗｽﾄｵｰﾀﾞｰ）あっ…
Be quiet!
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
うっせえぞ　さっきから
なにブツブツ言ってやがる
What the hell are you mumbling to yourself for?
Huh?
あっ… 何でもないって―
"Nothing!" says MISAKA says MISAKA covering her mouth.
ミサカはミサカは
口を押さえてみたり
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
ふ～ん…
ねえ 白井さん　オリジナルと
遺伝子レベルで寸分違(たが)わず―
Hey, Shirai-san.
The clones are genetically identical to the original, and even went through the exact same power development training.
全く同じ能力開発を
受けたというのに
So why didn't the clones reach the same level as the original?
クローンたちは どうして―
オリジナルと同じレベルに
なれないのかしら？
Doesn't this mean that there are other factors other than brain structure that matter?
これって 脳の構造以外の何かが
関わってるってことでしょう？
If we can find those, wouldn't non-humans also be able to use powers?
それを突き止めれば 人間以外でも
能力を扱えるってことにならない？
You only need intelligence on-par, or better than, that of human.
（結標）
人間と同等か それ以上の頭脳
The answer might be closer than you think.
案外
身近な所にあるかもしれないわよ
What are you saying...?
何を言ってますの？
（黒子）
ハッ…
まさか 機械に能力が宿るとでも？
Are you aiming to power-up the machine...?
フフッ… 機械は所詮 機械
A machine is merely a machine.
However, it can make a prediction.
でも 予測はできる
So long as we have an ultimate simulating machine that can recreate every possibility.
あらゆる現象を完全に再現する―
究極の
シミュレートマシンがあればね
I will investigate every possibility.
私は全ての可能性に問いかける
Can non-humans use Esper powers or not?
人間の代わりに 超能力が
扱える個体は存在するか否かを
For example, dolphins are called the humans of the sea,
例えば イルカは
“海のヒューマン”と呼ばれ
and the society of ants has a rigid set of rules and an order of command.
アリの社会には
厳格な規律と秩序がある
Psychic powers may not be limited to humans.
超能力は
人間の特権なんかじゃないはず
So why does it have to be humans?
ならば
なぜ人間でなくてはならないのか
I want to know the answer.
私は それを知りたい
And that is why I will use this Remnant to create a new Tree Diagram!
（結標）
そのために私は…
この残骸(レムナント)から―
新しい樹形図の設計者(ツリーダイアグラム)を
作り上げるの
（かみつく音）
（上条）いてーっ！
Ouch!
Why did you do that all of a sudden?!
（上条）
なんで いきなり そうなるんだよ？
こら！　離れろ！
Let go!
いや すんません 離れてください
インデックスさん！
I mean, I'm sorry! Please let go!
Index-san!
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）ひどいよ 当麻(とうま)
（上条）えっ？
You're so mean, Touma!
Huh?
I went out of the way to think of a tongue-twister too!
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
せっかく 私がステキな早口言葉を
考えたっていうのに
あのな　“当麻が遠くで
豆腐を遠目に見てトンマ”って
Okay, so...
"Touma is a twat that takes tofu from the toilet"...
No matter how you look at it, you're just making fun of me!
どう考えても 人のこと
バカにしてんだろう てめえ！
I was just joking...
（上条）
…て ウソです
あっ… 御坂？
Misaka...?
"I have a request," says MISAKA from the bottom of her heart as she faces you directly.
（御坂10032）お願いがあります
（上条）あっ…
…と ミサカは
あなたの顔をまっすぐに見て
心中を吐露します
"Please save the lives of MISAKA and her sisters."
ミサカとミサカの妹たちの命を
助けてください
I won't let that happen!
させない
That experiment...
あの実験だけは
絶対に再開させるわけにはいかない
No matter what, I won't allow it to start again!
Signs of a fight between two Espers in a restaurant in Area F?
（美琴）
“エリアＦのレストランで―”
“能力者同士の
衝突と見られる器物破損”？
ンッ… あのバカ
That idiot!
I've been looking for you, Shocker.
捜したぞ ビリビリ
Looking for me? Why?
“捜した”って… なんで…
なんで あんたが また…
Why are you always...
Hey.
（上条）おい
（美琴）あっ…
Let's go, Shocker.
いくぞ ビリビリ
You joined up with an external organization for that sole purpose?
（黒子）
あなたは
そのために外部の組織と？
Yes.
Even with the invaluable Remnant in my possession, I cannot repair it alone.
いくら価値ある残骸(レムナント)を手に入れても
私ひとりでは修復できないわ
That's why I need an organization with the technology, knowledge, and aim.
だから 技術と知識 そして
目的を持つ集団が必要だった
白井さん
あなたは どんな気分がした？
How did you feel, Shirai-san?
When you first gained possession of your power.
初めて その能力を手に入れたとき
To be honest, it was scary for me.
（結標）
正直 私は恐ろしかったわ
I was scared of how I could hold such power in my grasp.
こんな力が この手にあることが
何より怖かった
フッ… 人じゃなくても
私じゃなくてもいいのなら
It didn't have to come to a human, and certainly didn't have to come to me...
...so why do I have this power?
なぜ
私は こんな力を持っているの？
The children with me harbor the same anguish.
一緒にいたあの子たちも
私と同じ悩みを抱えているのよ
They curse their powers and continue to search for answers.
みんな 自分の能力を呪い
答えを求め続けていた　だから―
That's why they did not hesitate to cooperate with me, even if it meant becoming my shield.
私に協力し 盾となることさえ
いとわなかったの
（結標）
あなたにだって あるでしょう？
Has it not happened to you as well?
自分の能力を使って
誰かを傷つけてしまったことが
Where you've used your power to hurt someone.
（結標）
私には分かる
あなたは私に よく似てるもの
I can understand.
You and I are very much alike.
Well, Shirai-san?
どう？ 白井さん
If you also wish to know the truth, I'd be more than happy to fill you in.
共に真実を知る気があるなら
私は喜んで あなたを招待するわ
I refuse.
（黒子）お断りですわ
（結標）あっ…
Did you really think you could convince me, Shirai Kuroko, with such narcissistic words?
（黒子）
そんな自分の酔ったセリフで―
この白井黒子を丸め込めるとでも
思っていますの？
What a typical criminal.
さすがは悪党
言うことが小さいですわね
Everything you say is so sad.
Can't you understand?
（結標）
分からないの？
We Espers may not have needed to become monsters!
私たち 能力者なんて怪物に
ならずに済んだかもしれないのよ
Such a dangerous—
（結標）こんな危険な…
（黒子）ばかばかしい
Ridiculous!
One's power is nothing more than a power, no matter how far it is taken.
能力なんて
どこまで行っても ただの能力
力をどう使うのかは自分しだい
How you use your power is up to you.
そんな当たり前のことにも
気づかないなんて―
How stupid can you be not to realize something so obvious?
バカですの？　あなたは
You are scared of your own powers?
（黒子）
“力が怖い”？
“傷つけるから欲しくない”？
You do not want it because it may hurt someone?
フッ… 笑わせないでくださいな
Give me a break.
Whether you have a power or not does not change whether or not you are the type of person who will harm another.
（黒子）
力があろうとなかろうと―
あなたが
人を傷つける人間であることに―
変わりはありませんの
You are merely stating that you are special and no one else is.
結局 あなたの言いぐさは―
自分は特別で
周りは平凡だっていう―
You are nothing but a corrupted individual with a condescending attitude!
見下し精神丸出しの
汚い逃げでしかありませんわ！
I will now proceed to...
今から その腐った根性を…
...beat that rotten conviction of yours into shape!
たたき直してさし上げますわ！
イヤ…
No...
No... go away!
イヤ　来ないで…
I'll kill you...
殺す
You've destroyed all that I've lived for.
よくも この私を壊してくれたわね
Were it not for you, I would still have hope!
あなたがいなければ
私は まだ どうにでもなったのに
The maximum weight I can move with my Move Point is 4,520kg.
（結標）
私の“座標移動(ムーブポイント)”の最大重量は―
4,520キログラム
I can smash things into this building from a distance.
遠くからでも
ここへ たたき込めるわ
I'm certain I can make this building collapse, with you in it!
あなたは もちろん
このビルだって倒壊するでしょうね
あら　そのケース
まだ必要だったんですの？
Oh? You still needed that case?
I'll destroy you!
ぶち壊してあげる
Much like you've killed all that I am.
（結標）
あなたが私を壊したのだから
しっかり お返ししてあげるわね
I'll be sure to return the favor!
Onee-sama...
お姉様…
4,520kg...
4,520キログラム…
あっ この光は… お姉様！
This light...
Onee-sama!
Stay away, Onee-sama!
来てはいけません お姉様！
Kuroko!
（美琴）黒子！
（黒子）ハッ…
Who... are you...?
あなたは 一体…
（結標）
こちら Ａ001よりＭ000へ
This is A001 calling M000.
I'll make my report after confirming the code...
符号の確認のあと 状況の報告に…
（黄泉川(よみかわ)）
子供たぶらかせて 安全席から
ご見物とは いいご身分じゃん
Tricking the children and hiding in a safe place to watch the show...
You must be enjoying yourself!
What should I do?
どうすれば… どうすればいい？
What on Earth should I do?
Oh man...
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
つうかよ ちっとばっかしムリして
出てきたっていうのによ
I took all the trouble to come out here...
And what am I presented with? Some third-rate loser?
何だ？　このバカみたいな三下(さんした)は
No way...
（結標）
まさか アクセラレータ？
Accelerator?
The strongest Level 5 in Academy City that even the Railgun cannot defeat?
超電磁砲(レールガン)ですら
かなわないっていう―
学園都市最強のレベル５？
アア… ムリよ
I can't!
How can I...
あんなのに… あんなのに
まともに相対できるわけ…
How can I face someone like that?!
（結標）フフフッ… 知ってるわ
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）ああ？
I know!
Huh?
（結標）
あなたは
８月31日に力を失っているはず
You should have lost your power on August 31st.
That's right...
そう　今のあなたに
あの演算能力は もうない
You no longer have your calculation ability!
You no longer have the power you once had!
かつての力なんて
どこにもないのよ！
哀れだな お前
How pitiful.
So pitiful that I would hug you tight if you were being serious.
本気で言ってんだとしたら―
抱き締めたくなっちまうくらい
哀れだわ
It's true that I suffered brain damage that day.
確かに
俺は あの日 脳にダメージを負った
I now perform my calculations externally.
今じゃ 演算も外部に任せてる
However...
だがな 俺が弱くなったところで
The fact that I've gotten weaker doesn't mean that you've gotten any stronger!
別に お前が強くなったわけじゃ
ねえだろうがよ ああ？
It's useless!
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
悪いが こっから先は一方通行だ
From here on, the road belongs to me, Accelerator!
Just put your tail between your legs and get your ass back where you came from!
おとなしくシッポ巻きつつ泣いて
ぶざまに
元の居場所へ引き返しやがれ！
Well...
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
まあ…
In this state, I might be retiring from the title of strongest in Academy City...
確かに このザマじゃ
学園都市最強は引退かもしんねえが
それでも 俺は…
But even so...
I've decided that I will at least continue to call myself the strongest in front of that brat!
あのガキの前じゃ 最強を
名乗り続けることに決めてんだよ
ハァ… くそったれが
Damn it...
見て見て 当麻
Hey, look, Touma!
I've finally mastered how to buy juice!
ついに私はジュースの買い方を
マスターしたんだよ
Right.
What's wrong, Touma?
どうしたの？ 当麻
What do you mean, "What's wrong?"
どうしたも こうしたもあるか
（上条）
白井の見舞いに来てみれば…
I came to pay Shirai a visit...
So I decided to go see Misaka's sister instead...
しょうがねえから―
御坂妹のほうを訪ねてみれば…
不幸だ…
Such misfortune...
So what was the Remnant?
…で 結局 残骸(レムナント)って何なの？
さっきの裸の子と
カッコよく出ていったのに
You came out of the building looking all cool with the person who was just naked in your arms,
but you didn't actually figure out anything later, did you?
あのあと
何の収穫もなかったんだね
Yeah.
ああ　犯人らしい女の子は
誰かにボコボコ
Some girl who's apparently the culprit got all beaten up,
and what was in the case was smashed to pieces.
ケースの中身はバラバラだったしな
Sheesh, I wonder who did it?
（上条）
…たく
どこのどいつに やられたんだか
"So I heard that ultimately Yomikawa went outside and destroyed the 'Science Society.'"
（ﾗｽﾄｵｰﾀﾞｰ）
…で 結局 黄泉川が外で
科学結社をぶっ壊してきたんだって
"Apparently they had approached Amai Ao, too," says MISAKA says MISAKA while making a report.
なんか 天井亜雄(あまい あお)とも
接触があったらしいって―
ミサカはミサカは
レポートしてみたり
（あくび）
ああ そう
Oh, yeah?
"Hey, what's with the lack of enthusiasm?!" says MISAKA says MISAKA—
…て なに その気のない
スルーっぷりはって―
ミサカはミサカは…
（ｱｸｾﾗﾚｰﾀ）
うっせえな
You're way too loud.
ちったぁ沈黙って形で
感謝の気持ちを示しやがれ
Show me your appreciation by being quiet.
天気予報 当たりませんでしたわね
Today's weather forecast wasn't accurate either.
（美琴）
うん？　そうね
Yeah.
Onee-sama, I have realized something.
お姉様　私 気づきましたわ
That the place I saw yesterday was none other than your battlefield.
あの場所が
お姉様の戦っている世界なのだと
Kuroko...
黒子…
This whole incident stemmed from my own inexperience.
今回のことは
全て 黒子の未熟さが原因ですの
So Onee-sama, please keep smiling.
ですから
お姉様は笑っていてくださいな
I will use that smile as energy to get back on my feet once more.
黒子は その笑顔を糧に もう一度
立ち上がってみせますから
Yeah.
Thank you, Kuroko.
（美琴）
ありがとう 黒子
～♪
Next Episode
（上条）
大覇星(だいはせい)祭
The Daihaseisai.
The students are all fired up for the largest event in Academy City.
学園都市最大のイベントで
盛り上がる学生たち
その隙を突いて忍び寄る
新たな魔術師　そのねらいとは…
And a new magician that takes this chance to sneak in.
Her aim is...
次回 「大覇星祭」
Next time: "Daihaseisai."
科学と魔術が交差するとき
物語は始まる
When science and magic cross paths, this epic will begin!